JORDAN ASHWOOD

GRAPHIC DESIGNER & JR. FRONT-END DEVELOPER

CONTACT

614.330.8890

✓ jordanmace0124@gmail.com

Charleston, SC 29414

jordan-ashwood.netlify.app

PROFILE

Hi there! I am a highly creative and versatile Graphic Designer and Front-end Developer with a unique blend of artistic flair and technical expertise. I seamlessly combine my passion for design with my love for coding, resulting in visually stunning and user-friendly digital experiences. I am known for my strong work ethic, adaptability, and a relentless pursuit of new skills and knowledge. I'm a military veteran with a disciplined and organized approach to projects, coupled with a contagious enthusiasm for creative endeavors.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Fine Arts

Graphic Design University of Wisconsin — Oshkosh 2012 - 2016

Computer Science coursework completed: Intro to Computer Science and Programming, Object-Oriented Design and Programming I, Computer Architecture and Assembly Language, Data Structures, Calculus I, and Mathematics for Computer Science.

CERTIFICATIONS

Secret Clearance

Best in Show — Graphic Design SheCodes Certifications:

- Intro to Web Development
- Web Development
- · Advanced Web Development
- Responsive Web Development
- Advanced Responsiveness
- React Development
- Advanced React Development
- Introduction to Coding
- Front-end Developer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graphic & UX Designer/Jr. Developer/Cybersecurity Training Specialist

The Informatics Application Group | September 2019 - Present Charleston, SC

- Gather systems requirements and produce quality visualizations for client proposals and/or meetings
- Conceptualize and design graphics to accompany research articles
- · Create/design training materials for client projects across multiple medias
- Follow branding guidelines for projects and online graphics outlined by TIAG and clients
- Multi-project management and strategic planning while meeting various deadlines
- Provide guidance on the implementation of UX research techniques and testing activities to assess user behavior
- Produce high-quality solutions through flow diagrams, graphic designs, storyboards and site maps
- Elicit product specifications and consider user psychology in order to optimize
 the design of systems and products, to ensure they are safe, efficient, and
 comfortable for use.
- Contribute to system requirements planning and oversight with development teams
- Writing, testing, evaluating and maintaining code
- Provide real-time troubleshooting support and defect resolution through system testing and development
- · Well versed in object-oriented programming
- Extensive professional experience in corporate identity, branding, editorial, illustration, print production, typography, photography, videography, web design, logo creation, social media, and email marketing
- Create a variety of training materials for different user roles
- Monitor/track completion of training to enable/disable user access and accounts

SKILLS

Adobe Creative Cloud

Bootstrap

Branding

Color Theory

CSS

Figma

GitHub

HTML

Illustration

JavaScript

Keynote

Layout Design

Logo Creation

Mailchimp

Microsoft Suite

Photography

Presentation Design

Print Design

React.js

SharePoint

Social Media

Typography

Videography

Visual Studio Code

Vue.js

Web Design

Wordpress

HOBBIES

Coding

Cooking

Crafting

Photography

Singing

Traveling

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Art Director

Fox Cities Magazine | January 2018 - September 2019

Appleton, WI

- · Elicited requirements, created mock-ups and conducted demos with stakeholders
- Managed and developed the monthly and annual specialty publications
- Demonstrated effective coordination and project management skills by overseeing the work of multiple departments, during the production planning phase.
- Technical development and product milestone scheduling to ensure that project deadlines were met successfully.
- Created, implemented and maintained organizational procedures to increase efficiency
- Conceptualized social media campaigns, blog posts and contests to promote readership across various platforms

Lead Designer

Stellar Blue Technologies | July 2016 - January 2018

Neenah, WI

- Coordinated with clients to understand goals and planned design needs for web, video, and print media
- Collaborated with and managed various SMEs and technical resources to produce standout work efficiently
- Managed multiple projects and multiple resources within design and multimedia departments
- · Filmed, edited, and optimized videos for web
- Designed websites based on current UX trends
- · Created internal and external websites that were fully responsive

Information Technology Specialist

Army National Guard | February 2009 - February 2015

Wausau, WI

- Install, operate and maintain computer systems and local area networks (LAN).
- Perform system administration (SA) and maintain computers and servers within the computing environment (CE) and the network environment (NE).
- Perform network administration (NA); install, configure and maintain network equipment within the LAN.
- Install, operate, and maintain commercial off the shelf (COTS) equipment (i.e. routers, switches, desktop and laptop computers).
- Provide direct support for Information Dissemination and Content Staging.
- Perform Network Operations (NETOPS) Service Desk Management, which includes incident and problem processing, change request processing, availability management and user interaction.
- Assist in the planning, configuration, management, and monitoring of the wide area network (WAN)
- Acquired Security+, A+, CCNA I, CCNA II and Network+ Certification